[
  {
    "text": "Guido Gustavo Gozzano (19 December 1883 – 9 August 1916) was an Italian poet and writer. He was born in Turin, the son of Fausto Gozzano, an engineer,[1] and of Diodata Mautino",
    "spans": [
      {
        "text": "Guido Gustavo Gozzano",
        "is_entity": true,
        "label": "PERSON",
        "reason": "A person mentioned"
      },
      {
        "text": "19 December 1883",
        "is_entity": true,
        "label": "TIME_INTERVAL",
        "reason": "the point in time (in this context of birth)"
      },
      {
        "text": "9 August 1916",
        "is_entity": true,
        "label": "TIME_INTERVAL",
        "reason": "the point in time (in this context of death)"
      },
      {
        "text": "poet",
        "is_entity": true,
        "label": "ROLE",
        "reason": "in this context, the role or occupation the person had in his life"
      },
      {
        "text": "writer",
        "is_entity": true,
        "label": "ROLE",
        "reason": "in this context, the role or occupation the person had in his life"
      },
      {
        "text": "Fausto Gozzano",
        "is_entity": true,
        "label": "PERSON",
        "reason": "A person mentioned"
      },
      {
        "text": "engineer",
        "is_entity": true,
        "label": "ROLE",
        "reason": "in this context, the role or occupation the person had in his life"
      },
      {
        "text": "Diodata Mautino",
        "is_entity": true,
        "label": "PERSON",
        "reason": "A person mentioned"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "The British Museum is a public museum dedicated to human history, art and culture located in the Bloomsbury area of London.",
    "spans": [
      {
        "text": "British Museum",
        "is_entity": true,
        "label": "LOCATION",
        "reason": "A location, being a museum"
      },
      {
        "text": "human history",
        "is_entity": true,
        "label": "TOPIC",
        "reason": "in this context, refered as a topic the museum is dedicated"
      },
      {
        "text": "art",
        "is_entity": true,
        "label": "TOPIC",
        "reason": "in this context, refered as a topic the museum is dedicated"
      },
      {
        "text": "culture",
        "is_entity": true,
        "label": "TOPIC",
        "reason": "in this context, refered as a topic the museum is dedicated"
      },
      {
        "text": "Bloomsbury",
        "is_entity": true,
        "label": "LOCATION",
        "reason": "in this context, a location in which the museum is"
      },
      {
        "text": "London",
        "is_entity": true,
        "label": "LOCATION",
        "reason": "in this context, a location in which the other mentioned location exists"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "The Dialogue Concerning the Two Chief World Systems is a 1632 Italian-language book by Galileo Galilei comparing the Copernican system with the traditional Ptolemaic system.",
    "spans": [
      {
        "text": "Dialogue Concerning the Two Chief World Systems",
        "is_entity": true,
        "label": "INFORMATION_ENTITY",
        "reason": "title of an information entity (as a book)"
      },
      {
        "text": "1632",
        "is_entity": true,
        "label": "TIME_INTERVAL",
        "reason": "the date mentioned in the text"
      },
      {
        "text": "Galileo Galilei",
        "is_entity": true,
        "label": "PERSON",
        "reason": "A person mentioned"
      },
      {
        "text": "Italian language",
        "is_entity": true,
        "label": "SOCIAL_OBJECT",
        "reason": "in this context, it's a type of communication"
      },
      {
        "text": "Copernican system",
        "is_entity": true,
        "label": "SOCIAL_OBJECT",
        "reason": "a theory that is valid for humans"
      },
      {
        "text": "Ptolemaic system",
        "is_entity": true,
        "label": "SOCIAL_OBJECT",
        "reason": "a debated object, so something which is socially discussed"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "Uranium is a chemical element; it has symbol U and atomic number 92.",
    "spans": [
      {
        "text": "Uranium",
        "is_entity": true,
        "label": "PHYSICAL_OBJECT",
        "reason": "a chemical element"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "The University of Bologna is a public research university in Bologna, Italy, founded in 1088. ",
    "spans": [
      {
        "text": "University of Bologna",
        "is_entity": true,
        "label": "ORGANISATION",
        "reason": "An organisation, being a public research university"
      },
      {
        "text": "Bologna",
        "is_entity": true,
        "label": "LOCATION",
        "reason": "a city mentioned"
      },
      {
        "text": "Italy",
        "is_entity": true,
        "label": "LOCATION",
        "reason": "a nation in which the mentioned city is found"
      },
      {
        "text": "1088",
        "is_entity": true,
        "label": "TIME_INTERVAL",
        "reason": "the time point in which the foundation is considered to have happened"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "The University of Bologna is a public research university in Bologna, Italy, founded in 1088. ",
    "spans": [
      {
        "text": "University of Bologna",
        "is_entity": true,
        "label": "ORGANISATION",
        "reason": "An organisation, being a public research university"
      },
      {
        "text": "Bologna",
        "is_entity": true,
        "label": "LOCATION",
        "reason": "a city mentioned"
      },
      {
        "text": "Italy",
        "is_entity": true,
        "label": "LOCATION",
        "reason": "a nation in which the mentioned city is found"
      },
      {
        "text": "1088",
        "is_entity": true,
        "label": "TIME_INTERVAL",
        "reason": "the time point in which the foundation is considered to have happened"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "text": "The World Chess Championship 1984 was a match between challenger Garry Kasparov and defending champion Anatoly Karpov for the World Chess Championship title.",
    "spans": [
      {
        "text": "World Chess Championship 1984",
        "is_entity": true,
        "label": "ACTIVITY",
        "reason": "An activity in which people participate competing"
      },
      {
        "text": "Garry Kasparov",
        "is_entity": true,
        "label": "PERSON",
        "reason": "A person mentioned"
      },
      {
        "text": "Anatoly Karpov",
        "is_entity": true,
        "label": "PERSON",
        "reason": "Another mentioned person"
      },
      {
        "text": "defending champion",
        "is_entity": false,
        "label": "ROLE",
        "reason": "the role is a contextual one which is not relevant"
      },{
        "text": "challenger",
        "is_entity": false,
        "label": "ROLE",
        "reason": "the role is a contextual one in the match which is not relevant"
      },
      {
        "text": "World Chess Championship",
        "is_entity": true,
        "label": "ROLE",
        "reason": "the role the two people were competing for"
      }
    ]
  }
]